Stephen Hess Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Brookings Institution, 1961-2016 (Box 1-70)
  - Washington, D.C. reporters
    - Interviews
      - Solomon, John, 2006 (Box 67)
      - Sorensen, Jon, 2006 (Box 67)
      - Sprengelmeyer, Michael, 2005 (Box 67)
      - Stencel, Mark, undated (Box 67)
      - Stern, Seth Ross, 2006 (Box 67)
      - Stirland, Sarah, 2005 (Box 67)
      - Stone, Andrea, 2006 (Box 67)
      - Struglinski, Suzanne, 2006 (Box 67)
      - Suarez, Ray, 2007 (Box 67)
      - "T" transcripts, 2005-2006 (Box 67)
      - Taylor, Stuart, 2006 (Box 67)
      - Thomas, Helen, 2005 (Box 67)
      - Thomma, Steve, 2005 (Box 67)
      - Tobias, Ed, undated (Box 68)
      - Todd, Chuck, 2006 (Box 68)
      - Totenberg, Nina, 2006 See also mss83739_163_023 (Box 68)
      - Toto, Christian, 2006 (Box 68)
      - "W" transcripts, 2005-2006 (Box 68)
      - Walton-James, Vickie, 2006 (Box 68)
      - Weill-Greenberg, Elizabeth, 2005 (Box 68)
      - Whitesides, John, 2005 (Box 68)
      - Whittle, Richard, 2006 (Box 68)
      - Wiedenbauer, Heidi, 2005 (Box 68)
      - Wiley, Ed, 2005 (Box 68)
      - Williams, Louis Alan "Pete", 2006 See also mss83739_163_010 (Box 68)
      - Wilner, Elizabeth, 2005 (Box 68)
      - Wolffe, Richard, 2005 (Box 68)
      - Woodlee, Yolanda, 2006 (Box 68)
      - "Z" transcripts, 2006 (Box 68)
      - Zamora, Amanda, 2006 (Box 68)
      - Zuckman, Jill, 2006 (Box 68)
    - Telephone survey of Washington, D.C. reporters
      - July, 1987, (2 folders) (Box 68)
      - July, 1987, (3 folders) (Box 69)
      - Aug., 1987, (3 folders) (Box 69)
      - 1989, (1 folder) (Box 69)
      - 1989, (2 folders) (Box 70)
    - White House reporters survey, 1991 (Box 70)
  - "Washington, D.C. Reporters Redex," newspapers
    - Atlanta Journal-Constitution, 1998 (Box 70)
    - Boston Globe, 1998 (Box 70)
    - Dallas Morning News, 1998 (Box 70)
    - Final report and data, 1998 (Box 70)
    - New York Times, 1998 (Box 70)
    - San Diego Union-Tribune, 1998 (Box 70)
    - Television and raw data, 1998 (Box 70)
- George Washington University School of Media and Public Affairs Interviews, 2006-2009
  Digital videos of interviews with authors and journalists, conducted as part of Stephen Hess's course on career patterns in journalism at the George Washington University School of Media and Public Affairs.
  Arranged alphabetically by name.
  Some files contain video playback errors, such as dropouts, interference, static or color shifting, and audio errors, such as pops, clicks or clipping. Files are as they were received from the donor.
  - Alexander, Andrew, 2009, Apr. 1 See also Container32 and See also Container 59, mss83739_163_028
  - Alexander, Andrew, 1 Apr. 2009, mss83739_163_029
    Duplicate of mss83739_163_028
  - Bradley, David, 5 Nov. 2008, mss83739_163_030
  - Burt, Richard, R., 7 Nov. 2007 See also Container 34, mss83739_163_031
  - Clift, Eleanor, 3 Dec. 2008, mss83739_163_036
  - Desta, Dereje, Alberto Avendano, Denise Rolark Barnes, and Alexandra Moe, 11 Feb. 2009, mss83739_163_037
  - Dykstra, Peter, 25 Feb. 2009, mss83739_163_038
  - Easton, Nina, 5 Mar. 2009, mss83739_163_039
  - Eisele, Albert, 11 Mar. 2009 See also Container 61, mss83739_163_040
  - Elfin, Dana and Harold Pskowski, 5 Mar. 2008 See also Container 61, mss83739_163_041
  - Elving, Ronald D., 15 Oct. 2008 See also Container 61, mss83739_163_042
  - Glass, Andrew J. and Andrew Alexander, 2008, Feb. 6 See also Container 32, See also Container 37, and See also Container 59, mss83739_163_027
  - Graham, Fred P., 16 Apr. 2008 See also Container 38, mss83739_163_044
  - Greenhouse, Linda, 1 Oct. 2008, mss83739_163_043
  - Guest, Kathy, 20 Feb. 2008, mss83739_163_025
  - Gwaltney, Corbin, 10 Oct. 2007, mss83739_163_026
  - Hume, Brit, 17 Oct. 2007 See also Container 39 and See also Container 63, mss83739_163_003
  - Jaroslovsky, Rich and John J. Fialka, 13 Feb. 2008 See also Container37 and See also Container 39, mss83739_163_004
  - Kalb, Bernard and Marvin L., 3 Oct. 2007 See also Container 39, mss83739_163_033
  - Kelley, Kitty, 8 Oct. 2008, mss83739_163_034
  - Kiplinger, Knight A., 5 Dec. 2007 See also Container 64, mss83739_163_035
  - Lowenstein, Doug, 24 Oct. 2007 See also Container 40, mss83739_163_001
  - McGann, Laura, 4 Feb. 2009, mss83739_163_005
  - Merry, Robert W., 28 Nov. 2007, mss83739_163_002
  - Myers, Dee Dee, 2006, mss83739_163_024
    Audio file only.
  - Nessen, Ron, 18 Feb. 2009, mss83739_163_014
  - Olson, Lynne and Stanley Cloud, 27 Feb. 2008 See also Container 43, mss83739_163_012
  - Patterson, Kathy and Penny Girard Pagano, 26 Sept. 2007 See also Container 43, mss83739_163_013
  - Pomfret, John, 29 Oct. 2008, mss83739_163_011
  - Roberts, Steven V., 19 Sept. 2007 See also Container 44, mss83739_163_021
  - Rosen, James, 8 Apr. 2009 See also Container 66, mss83739_163_022
  - Rosenstiel, Tom, Sept. 2008, mss83739_163_018
  - Schweid, Barry and Don Oberdorfer, 9 Apr. 2008 See also Container 42, mss83739_163_019
  - Shafer, Jack, David Carr, and Erik Wemple, 19 Nov. 2008, mss83739_163_032
  - Shannon, Elaine and Ted Gest, 12 Mar. 2008 See also Container 37 and See also Container 45, mss83739_163_020
  - Shepard, Alicia C., 30 Jan. 2008 See also Container 45, mss83739_163_017
  - Smith, Hedrick, 31 Oct. 2007 See also Container 45, mss83739_163_015
  - Smith, Stephen G., 28 Jan. 2009 See also Container 67, mss83739_163_016
  - Stein, Sam, 25 Mar. 2009, mss83739_163_006
  - Stern, Carl, 23 Jan. 2008 See also Container 46, mss83739_163_007
  - Sussman, Barry, 24 Sept. 2008, mss83739_163_008
  - Tolchin, Martin 12 Sept. 2007 See also Container 46, mss83739_163_009
  - Totenberg, Nina, 2 Apr. 2008 See also Container 68, mss83739_163_023
  - Williams, Louis Alan "Pete", 15 Apr. 2009 See also Container 68, mss83739_163_010
- White House Files, 1967-1971, 2009 (Box 71-101)
  Alphabetical, chronological, personal, and subject files from Stephen Hess's tenure as Deputy Assistant to the President for Urban Affairs in the Nixon administration.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic and alphabetically by name, topic, or chronologically therein.
  - Action memoranda, Jan.-Oct., 1969, (7 folders) (Box 71)
  - Alphabetical file
    - "A" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 72)
    - Agnew, Spiro T. (memorandum for the Vice President), 1969 (Box 72)
    - Anderson, Paul (memoranda), 1969 (Box 72)
    - Ayres, Robert U., 1969 (Box 72)
    - "B" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 72)
    - Black list, 1969 (Box 72)
    - Blair, Charles Stanley, 1969 (Box 72)
    - Bookbinder, Hyman Harry, 1969 (Box 72)
    - Booth, Arch Newell, 1969 (Box 72)
    - Burns, Arthur F., 1969, (2 folders) (Box 72)
    - "C" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - Cole, Kenneth (White House Staff Secretary), 1969, (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - "D" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - Democratic National Committee platform, 1968 (Box 73)
    - "E" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - Ehrlichman, John, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 74)
    - "F" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 74)
    - Finch, Robert H., 1969, (2 folders) (Box 74)
    - Finkbeiner, Carty, 1969 (Box 74)
    - Finn, Chester E., Jr., 1969 (Box 74)
    - Flanigan, Peter M., 1969 (Box 74)
    - "G" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 74)
    - Goggin, Terrence P. and Walter C. Hendrix, 1969-1970 (Box 75)
    - Goldberg, Dorothy Kurgans, 1969 (Box 75)
    - "H" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 75)
    - Harlow, Bryce Nathaniel, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 75)
    - Hawkins, Augustus F., 1969 (Box 75)
    - Higby, Lawrence M., 1969 (Box 75)
    - "I" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 75)
    - Intergovernmental Cooperation Act, 1968 (Box 75)
    - Invitations, 1969 (Box 75)
    - "J" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 75)
    - Jaycees (United States), 1968 (Box 76)
    - "K" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 76)
    - Klein, Herbert G., 1969 (Box 76)
    - Kurtz, Seymour, 1969 (Box 76)
    - "L" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 76)
    - Ladd, Bruce Clinton Jr., 1969 (Box 76)
    - Lerner, Michael, 1969 (Box 76)
    - "Mc" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 76)
    - "M" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 77)
    - Mattel Toy Makers, Inc., 1969 (Box 77)
    - Mayer, Jean, 1969 (Box 77)
    - Mayors, 1969 (Box 77)
    - Memorandum (White House staff), 1969 (Box 77)
    - Merriam, Robert E., 1969 (Box 77)
    - Mitchell, John N., 1969 (Box 77)
    - "N" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 77)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1968-1969 (Box 77)
    - New York, N.Y., 1968-1969 (Box 78)
    - "O" general, 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box 78)
    - "P" general, 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box 78)
    - Peterson, Peter G., 1969 (Box 78)
    - "R" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 78)
    - Raines, Franklin D., 1969 (Box 78)
    - Romney, George W., 1969 (Box 78)
    - "S" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 79)
    - Silha, Otto A., 1969 (Box 79)
    - Sloan, Hugh W., 1969 (Box 79)
    - Sterling Institute (Lawrence J. Brailsford and David C. McClelland), 1969 (Box 79)
    - Sullivan, Leon Howard, 1969 (Box 79)
    - "T" general, 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box 79)
    - Timmons, William Evan and Joel T. Broyhill, 1969 (Box 79)
    - Toner, Albert P., 1969 (Box 79)
    - "U" general, 1968-1969, (2 folders) (Box 79)
    - "V" general, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 79)
    - Veneman, John G., 1969 (Box 79)
    - Volpe, John A., 1969 (Box 79)
    - "W" general, 1969-1970, (1 folder) (Box 79)
    - "W" general, 1969, (1 folder) (Box 80)
    - Wiener, Anthony J., 1969 (Box 80)
    - "X, Y, Z" general, 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box 80)
  - Chronological file
    - Jan. 1969 (Box 80)
    - Feb. 1969, (2 folders) (Box 80)
    - Mar. 1969 (Box 80)
    - Apr. 1969 (Box 80)
    - May 1969 (Box 80)
    - June 1969 (Box 81)
    - July 1969 (Box 81)
    - Aug. 1969 (Box 81)
    - Sept. 1969 (Box 81)
    - Oct. 1969 (Box 81)
    - Nov. 1969 (Box 81)
    - Dec. 1969 (Box 81)
  - Index to files, 1969 (Box 81)
  - Personal file
    - Asia trip
      - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 82)
      - Hong Kong, 1969, (5 folders) (Box 82)
      - Press clippings, 1969 (Box 82)
      - Receipts, 1969 (Box 82)
      - Schedules, 1969 (Box 82)
      - Singapore, 1969 (Box 82)
      - Toyko, Japan, 1968-1969, (2 folders) (Box 83)
    - Biography and photographs, 1969 (Box 83)
    - Chronological material
      - Jan. 1969 (Box 83)
      - Feb. 1969 (Box 83)
      - Mar. 1969 (Box 83)
      - Apr. 1969 (Box 83)
      - May 1969 (Box 83)
      - June 1969 (Box 83)
      - July 1969 (Box 84)
      - Aug. 1969 (Box 84)
      - Sept. 1969 (Box 84)
      - Oct.-Nov. 1969 (Box 84)
      - Dec. 1969 (Box 84)
      - Jan.-Feb. 1970 (Box 84)
    - Employment records, 1969 (Box 84)
    - Invitations, 1969 (Box 84)
    - Official expenses, 1969 (Box 84)
    - Romania and Yugoslavia, 1971 (Box 84)
    - Venezuela, 1970, (4 folders) (Box 85)
  - Referrals, pending, 1969 (Box 85)
  - Richard Nixon Presidential Library and Museum Oral History Interview with Stephen Hess, 2009, (Part 1 of 2); mss83739_163_045
  - Richard Nixon Presidential Library and Museum Oral History Interview with Stephen Hess, 2009, (Part 2 of 2); mss83739_163_046
  - Subject file
    - Action for Boston Community Development (ABCD), 1967-1969 (Box 85)
    - Administration, 1969 (Box 85)
    - Advisory Council on Executive Organization, 1969 (Box 86)
    - Air transportation message, 1969 (Box 86)
    - American Indians, 1968-1969 (Box 86)
    - Anglo-American Conference on the Evaluation of Social Action Programmes, Ditchley Park, United Kingdom, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 86)
    - Anti-ballistic missile (ABM), 1969 (Box 86)
    - Appointments, pending, 1969 (Box 86)
    - Army War College (U.S.), undated (Box 86)
    - Bacon, Jim, 1969 (Box 86)
    - Building and construction industry labor, 1969 (Box 86)
    - Business economics, 1969 (Box 86)
    - Census data, 1969-1970 (Box 86)
    - Center for Urban Studies, University of Chicago, Doris B. Holleb, 1969 (Box 86)
    - City profiles, Ben Holman, 1969 (Box 87)
    - Civil disorders, 1969 (Box 87)
    - Civil rights, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 87)
    - Classified material handling, 1969 (Box 87)
    - Clippings, 1969 (Box 87)
    - Commission on Goals for 1976, 1969 (Box 87)
    - Congressional relations, 1969 (Box 87)
    - Consumer affairs, 1969 (Box 87)
    - Councils, committees, and commissions, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 87)
    - Councils, committees, and commissions, 1969, (1 folder) (Box 88)
    - Domestic policy speech, 8 Aug. 1969 (Box 88)
    - Domestic programs, 1969 (Box 88)
    - Draft message, 13 May 1969 (Box 88)
    - Education, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 88)
    - Environment, 1969 (Box 88)
    - Ethnic and substandard groups, 1969 (Box 88)
    - Executive orders, 1969 (Box 88)
    - Family assistance program, 1969 (Box 88)
    - Family security system, 1967-1969 (Box 88)
    - Federal aid and revenue sharing, 1969-1970 (Box 89)
    - Federal government organizations, 1969 (Box 89)
    - Federal mediation and conciliation, 1969 (Box 89)
    - Finance and budget appropriations, 1969 (Box 89)
    - Food and nutrition, 1969 (Box 89)
    - Foreign aid message, 1969 (Box 89)
    - General Services Administration, 1969 (Box 89)
    - Governmental reorganization, 1969 (Box 89)
    - Grants message, 1969 (Box 89)
    - Groups seen by Stephen Hess, 1969 (Box 89)
    - Health, 1969, (3 folders) (Box 89)
    - Hesburgh, Theodore M., 1969 (Box 89)
    - Housing, 1969 (Box 90)
    - Housing and urban affairs, 1968-1969 (Box 90)
    - Hunger, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 90)
    - Inaugural address of President Richard M. Nixon, 1969 (Box 90)
    - Inflation, 1969 (Box 90)
    - Internal migration, 1969 (Box 90)
    - International education, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 90)
    - Interstate Commerce Commission, 1969 (Box 90)
    - Judicial and legal matters, 1969 (Box 90)
    - Justice, 1969 (Box 91)
    - Lee County Community Action Agency, Inc., 1968 (Box 91)
    - Legislative proposals, 1969 (Box 91)
    - Life insurance companies, 1969 (Box 91)
    - Local governments, 1969 (Box 91)
    - Manpower program, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 91)
    - Mass transit, 1969 (Box 91)
    - Mayors, 1969 (Box 91)
    - Meetings and conferences, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 91)
    - Memoranda for the president, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 92)
    - Mexican-Americans, 1969 (Box 92)
    - Migration, 1969 (Box 92)
    - Mine safety, 1969 (Box 92)
    - Minority business enterprise, 1969 (Box 92)
    - Model cities, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 92)
    - Morgan, Edward L., 1969 (Box 92)
    - Moynihan, Daniel P., 1969, (4 folders) (Box 93)
    - Narcotics, 1969 (Box 93)
    - National Advisory Council on Economic Opportunity, 1969 (Box 93)
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), 1969 (Box 93)
    - National Alliance of Businessmen, 1969 (Box 93)
    - National security and defense, 1969 (Box 93)
    - Negro leadership, 1969 (Box 93)
    - Neighborhood Center Pilot Program (NCPP), 1969 (Box 93)
    - "New Towns" project, 1969 (Box 93)
    - North Atlantic Council (NATO), 1969 (Box 93)
    - Occupational health and safety, 1969 (Box 93)
    - Office of Child Development, 1969 (Box 93)
    - Office of Intergovernmental Relations, 1969 (Box 93)
    - Organized crime, 1969 (Box 93)
    - Philadelphia plan, Labor Department, 1969 (Box 94)
    - Photographs of President Nixon, 1969 (Box 94)
    - Plans for Progress, 1969 (Box 94)
    - "Police, Politics, and Race: the New York City Referendum on Civilian Review," 1969 (Box 94)
    - Political affairs, 1969 (Box 94)
    - Population and family planning, 1969 (Box 94)
    - Population of the United States, 1969 (Box 94)
    - Poverty, 1969 (Box 94)
    - Power emergencies, 1969 (Box 94)
    - Presidential directives, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 94)
    - Presidential election, 1968 (Box 94)
    - Presidential memoranda, 1969 (Box 94)
    - Press conferences, 1969 (Box 94)
    - Press releases, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 94)
    - Public relations, 1969-1970, (4 folders) (Box 95)
    - Racial categories statistics, 1969 (Box 95)
    - Rebuilding, 1969 (Box 95)
    - Regional commissions, 1969 (Box 95)
    - Regional councils, 1969 (Box 95)
    - Regulatory agencies, 1969 (Box 95)
    - Reports and statistics, 1969 (Box 95)
    - Republican mayors and elections, 1969 (Box 95)
    - Republican platform, 1968 (Box 95)
    - Restructuring of government service systems, regional boundaries, 1969, (3 folders) (Box 96)
    - Revenue sharing, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 96)
    - Rockefeller recommendations, 1969 (Box 96)
    - Safety and health message, 1969 (Box 96)
    - Scheuer, James H., 1969 (Box 96)
    - Science Advisory Office, 1969 (Box 96)
    - Sciences, 1969 (Box 96)
    - Selective Service system, 1969 (Box 96)
    - Small Business Administration, 1969 (Box 96)
    - Social Security program, 1969 (Box 96)
    - Speeches, 1969 (Box 96)
    - Staff and department briefs, 1969 (Box 96)
    - Standards of ethical conduct for government officers and employees, 1969 (Box 97)
    - "A Strategy of Effective Government: the Nixon Administration's First Six Months," 1969 (Box 97)
    - Summer youth programs, 1969 (Box 97)
    - Task force reports, 1968-1969 (Box 97)
    - Task forces for 1970, 1969 (Box 97)
    - Tax reform proposals, Treasury Department, 1969 (Box 97)
    - Training Incentive Payments Program, New York, N.Y., 1969 (Box 97)
    - Transpacific air route case, 1969 (Box 97)
    - Transportation, highways, 1969 (Box 97)
    - Under secretaries group, 1969 (Box 97)
    - United States Commission on Civil Rights, 1969-1970, (3 folders) (Box 97)
    - Urban affairs, voluntary action, 1969 (Box 98)
    - Urban public transportation, 1969 (Box 98)
    - Veterans affairs, 1969 (Box 98)
    - Voluntary action, 1969 (Box 98)
    - Voting rights, 1969 (Box 98)
    - Welfare, 1969, (5 folders) (Box 98)
    - Welfare, 1969, (3 folders) (Box 99)
    - White House fellows, 1969 (Box 99)
    - White House parking permits, 1969 (Box 99)
    - White House staff mess, 1969 (Box 99)
    - White House tours, 1969 (Box 99)
    - White House Transportation Agency, 1969 (Box 99)
    - White House Urban Affairs Council, 1969 (Box 99)
    - Youth, 1969 (Box 99)
    - Youth Advisory Committee, 1969 (Box 99)
  - Urban Affairs Council
    - Meetings, 1969, (1 folder) (Box 99)
    - Meetings, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - Miscellany, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - Paper on first hundred days, 1969 (Box 100)
    - "The Present and Promise of the Urban Affairs Council," 1969 (Box 100)
    - Press releases, 1969 (Box 100)
    - Progress report to the president, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - Reports and statements, 1969 (Box 100)
    - Research committee, 1969 (Box 101)
    - Staff memoranda, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 101)
    - Subcommittees, 1969 (Box 101)
    - Transportation, 1969 (Box 101)